麦克斯  我等不及要回家
Max, I can't wait to go home
非法下载那个行为艺术的纪录片了
and illegally download that documentary about performance art.
我也迫不及待想回家
And I can't wait to go home
看《甜心波波来啦》
and watch Here Comes Honey Boo Boo.
但你得先跟我看这纪录片
But first, you have to see this.
她的名字叫玛丽娜·阿布拉莫维奇
Her name's Marina Abramovic.
在20世纪90年代  她和她的男友
In the '90s, she and her boyfriend
共同创作了名为《对峙》的作品
did this piece called Confrontation
-内容就是两人不停互扇耳光  -是吗
- where they just slapped each other's faces for days. -Oh, yeah?
我妈妈和她男友也干过这"艺术"
My mom and her boyfriend did that too,
不过他们的作品名为《谁抽了最后一根烟》
but they called it, "Who smoked the last cigarette"
不  我说真的  这是纯艺术呀
No, really, it was pure art.
她可是个天才
She's a genius.
我们俩现在也来搞"艺术"如何
How about you and I do a little art right now?
她们在干嘛
What are they doing?
我觉得她们可能在演绎
I think they might be doing a scene
情欲小说《五十度灰》里面的场景
from Fifty shades of grey.
-好了  住手  -好吧
- Ah, okay, stop. - Okay.
这巴掌是因为你拐我跟你录
That's for suggesting we make a lip-synch video
《Call Me Maybe》的假唱影片
to Call Me Maybe.
怎么了  伙计  你看起来很低落呀
What's up, my man? You look pretty down.
厄尔  我远在韩国的妈妈
My mother in korea is working
快让我精神崩溃了
my last nerve, you know, Earl?
我只是假客套问一下  没想到你会回我
Well, uh, I didn't expect a back and forth here.
麦克斯  你来帮我接一下吧
Uh, Max, do you wanna move in?
阿憨  你不能老让你妈骑你头上欺负你
Han, you can't let your mommy keep bullying you.
要起身反抗  你都53岁了
Stand up to her. You're a 53-year-old man.
麦克斯  我才29岁
Max, I am 29.
怎么可能
What?
我就是29岁呀
I am 29.
那你是怎么了  跟本杰明·巴顿一样吗
What do you got, a case of the Benjamin Buttons?
卡洛琳  阿憨说他才29岁
Caroline, Han says he's 29.
怎么可能
What?
阿憨  你确定吗
Han, are you sure?
当然  你们为什么觉得我很老呢
Yes, what makes you think I'm older?
从头到脚都老啊  你的发型  衣着
Well, everything-- your hair, your clothes,
你像老人一样开5块钱的生日红包支票给我
The $5 check you gave me for my birthday.
您好  有何能为您效劳
Hi, can I help you?
哇  这语气真诚得我都要掉眼泪了
Ooh, that sounded so sincere.
等你坐到我那区  你就会见识到真实的我啦
Well, when you're in my section, you'll meet the real me.
我有个问题
I have one question.
你想活吗
Do you wanna live?
以今天来说嘛...  都可以吧
Actually, today, I could go either way.
瞧见了吗
You see this?
去叫餐厅里的所有人把包里的财物
Go around the diner and have everyone fill it
都扔进去这袋子
with the contents of their purse,
你乖乖合作  大家都能平安无事
and if you do, nobody gets hurt.
好啦  知道了
Okay, okay, okay,
但我不知道你能收多少钱上来哦
but, uh, I don't know how much you're gonna collect here.
因为这里大部分的顾客都是用硬币
I mean, most of these customers pay with coins
或自家花园的新鲜番茄买单
or fresh tomatoes from their garden.
厄尔  听着
Uh, Earl, listen up.
那边穿着大衣的男人是来抢劫的
We're being robbed by that man in the suit,
他要求大家把财物都丢到这个袋子里
and he wants everyone to empty their stuff into this bag.
麦克斯  抢人与被抢我都有经验
Uh, Max, I've been on both sides of this situation,
顺着他的意才是上策
and the best thing to do is play along.
卡洛琳  我要跟你说件事
Okay, Caroline, I'm gonna tell you something,
但我不想你做出过激反应
and I don't want you to react.
我就知道你的肚子会被人搞大  靠
I knew you were gonna get pregnant. Damn it!
算了
All right, fine.
-我们可以一起度过这个难关  -不是啦
- We'll get through this together. - No!
听着  我们被人抢劫了
Look, we're being robbed,
那个大衣人可能有枪
and that guy in the suit might have a gun.
别这样  照我说的做  然后保持冷静
No, no--just do what I say, and stay calm.
把你钱包里的东西都倒进这个垃圾袋
I need you to empty your purse into the trash bag.
我真不敢相信刚省出2块钱
I can't believe this is happening
就被人抢走了
just when I saved $2.
麦克斯  我不能死
Max, I can't die,
就算死  也不想死在这丑爆的制服里
and I certainly can't die in this ugly uniform.
你穿是很好看啦  但...
I mean, it looks good on you.
你是不是心脏病发了
Are you having a heart attack?
我尿尿
I'm peeing.
什么意思
What do you mean?
我不是吓"屎"了  我是吓"尿"了
I'm really freaked out, and I'm peeing.
我还停不下来了
I can't stop!
快止住  夹紧
Just stop, stop! Clench it.
好的
Okay.
办不到
No, can't.
从柜台后面站出来
Step out from behind the counter.
抱歉  先生  办不到
Sorry, sir, I can't.
-为什么  -因为我在尿尿
- Why? - Well, um, I'm peeing.
还没尿完啊
Still?
姑娘们  让开  让我来收拾这个混...
Out of the way, girls. I'll take down this--
站离他远点
Get away from him.
小姐  你最好现在就从柜台后面出来
Miss, you need to get out from behind the counter now
-否则我就...  -你要人质抓她吧  别抓我
- before I--  - Uh, please take her, not me.
-发生什么事了  -阿憨  人家来抢劫
- What's happening? - Han, we're being robbed.
抱歉打扰您抢劫了
So sorry.
我腰包里的东西
Please take everything
请您通通拿去吧
that is in my manny-pack.
可以求您让我保留念珠吗
Would it be possible if I took my prayer beads out?
它是我家的传家宝  传了好多好多代了
They've been in my family for hundreds and hundreds of--
小混球  想都别想啊
I don't think so, homeboy.
敢在太岁头上动土  狗东西
You're in my house now, bitch.
袋子里就剩这个了
Here's what's left in the bag.
抱歉  没找到你的尊严
Nope, sorry. I don't see your dignity.
麦克斯  别这样
Max, don't.
难道我现在身穿洗碗工的大白褂还不够丢脸吗
Isn't it enough that I'm wearing dishwasher whites
这玩意就是伴随着狐臭出生的
that have been around since the invention of B.O.?
快瞧瞧  拖把居然被某液体腐蚀了
Oh, look at that, something ate right through the swiffer,
罪魁祸首貌似不是漂白剂哟
and I don't think it was the bleach.
犯下奇耻大辱  你以后怎么做人呀
How will you ever live with the shame?
你能相信是那个男人救了我们吗
Can you believe that is the man who saved us?
就是  完全没想到他会掏枪
Yeah, I did not see a gun coming.
我可以想象双节棍  忍者烟雾
I saw nunchucks, ninja smoke,
或者拉人头发  但没想到他会掏枪
maybe some hairpulling, but not a gun.
晚安  姑娘们
Well, good night, ladies.
今晚的我们  都非常勇敢
I thought we all acted very brave tonight.
某些人除外
Well, some of us.
是呀  我刚精神受创  所以失禁了
Oh, yeah, I had a trauma, and I urinated.
哈哈哈  笑死人可以了吧
Ha ha! That's hilarious.
是啊  你可能需要心理咨询
Yeah, you might need some counseling.
在我去"被人当过人肉盾牌"的互助小组路上
I could drop you off at a therapist on the way to my
可以顺路带你见心理医生
"I was a human shield" support group.
你什么时候才能忘了这事啊
Am I ever gonna live this down?
十分钟前才发生的事啊
It happened, like, ten minutes ago.
好吧  说别的
Okay, let's move on.
看  有人留了张电影院的免费爆米花券呢
Oh, look, someone left a coupon for free movie popcorn.
我非常想远离一切  尤其是经过了这...
Oh, I'd love to escape to a movie after my--
我就想远离这一切
Well, I'd just love to escape.
这年头看电影要多少钱啊  要200块吗
How much are movies now, like 200 bucks?
如果你跟我去  就分文不花
Unless you go with me, in which case, it is free.
我明天带你去吧
I'll take you tomorrow.
我从2岁就开始偷溜进电影院了
I've been sneaking into theaters since I was two.
当时我偷爬进去看《小美人鱼》
I crawled into The little mermaid
还一手揣着一袋麦圈
with a sack full of cheerios
和满满一奶瓶的健怡可乐呢
and a baby bottle full of diet coke.
栗宝  你知道吗
You know, chestnut,
你是我撑过那场劫案的唯一精神支柱
the only thing that got me through that robbery was you.
我一直在想"我挂了  谁来照顾你"
I kept thinking, "who will take care of you?"
毕竟你完全不能依靠金发自私妞
Because you can't count on blondie selfish-pants
她不仅把我当人肉盾牌  还尿了裤子
who used me as a human shield and then peed herself.
别告诉栗宝我失禁的事
Do not tell chestnut I peed myself.
他是我旧圈子里  唯一还跟我说话的了
He's the only one from my circle who still talks to me.
正如我刚说的  栗宝
As I was saying, chestnut,
但她却只想着自己
but she put herself first,
没关系  我不介意
And that's okay. It's fine.
麦克斯  我真没想到你会在意这事
Max, I'm surprised you're even affected by this.
你不是婴儿时期就中过弹了吗
I mean, weren't you shot as a baby?
我觉得你好像告诉过我的呀
I feel like you told me that.
我是说我婴儿期就喝烈酒[中弹]了
No, I told you I drank shots as a baby.
我妈不喜欢独自喝酒
My mother hated to drink alone.
好了  我们该看哪部免费电影呢
Okay, what free movie should we see?
要不看有范宁姐妹的吧
Maybe something with a Fanning in it?
我无所谓
I'll see anything
3D除外
unless it's in 3D.
如果有"东西"要在我面前飞来飞去
I mean, if something's gonna be flying at my face,
起码得先请我吃顿牛排
I'd better get a free prime rib out of it.
我们应该怎么做呢  麦克斯  怎么做呀
So what do we do, Max? What do we do?
躲进后巷  等待最佳时机
Hide in the back alley till the coast is clear,
门一打开  就冲进去吗
and when the door opens, make a break for it?
不必  现在又不是20世纪40年代
No, 'cause it's not the 1940s.
我们就直接走到带位员的面前
We just go right up in the usher's face,
编个借口  踏着自信又有所图谋的步伐进去
make an excuse, and then boldly walk with purpose.
好吧  那你演给我看
Okay, well, just show me how.
你可以指导我  我演过不少话剧呢
You can direct me. I've done a lot of plays.
我可以用"变身为大家闺秀前的卖花女"姿态走路
I could do my "Eliza Doolittle before she was civilized" walk.
你好  大人[穷人腔]
Hello, governor.
哇  丑爆了  我真想自戳双目
Wow, that was just ugly. I wish I hadn't seen it.
好了  看我的
All right, just watch me.
走  走  走  甩下头发  继续走
Walk, walk, walk, hair flip, walk, walk.
很好  但是甩头发的时候轻点  维罗·史密斯
Good, but easy on the hair flip, Willow Smith.
你们好呀  姑娘们
Oh, hi, girls.
我都听说了
Oh, I heard what happened.
麦克斯  你被人推到枪口上
Max, you got pushed in front of a gun.
想必非常恼羞成"尿"吧
You must be very pissed.
卡洛琳  你这身衣服真漂亮
Caroline, oh, what a nice outfit.
如果按1到10评分  我会给你个8分
On a scale of one to ten, you're an eight.
姑娘尿8不是罪
Get it? Urinate.
你都是听谁说的呀
How do you even know what happened?
听奥列格说的呀  那时候我们在楼上
Oh, well, Oleg told me when we were upstairs
玩"藏鸡鸡"的游戏
playing "hide the penis,"
我们捧腹大笑  差点失禁
And we laughed so hard, we almost peed ourselves,
但我们没尿  因为我们不是你
but we didn't because we're not you.
其实我们要去看电影
Actually, we're going to a movie.
那不错呀
Oh, well, that's nice.
希望你有穿上成人的尿不湿
I hope you're gonna wear your big girl pants.
-麦克斯  -干嘛  这又傻又好笑
- Max. - What? It's silly and funny.
她就像波兰版的搞笑放屁垫
She's like a polish fart cushion.
如果能让你感觉好过点
Look, if it makes you feel any better,
我敢说她尿尿的笑话用完了
there can't be any pee jokes left.
你们准备看什么电影呀
What are you seeing,
尿尿-13级的电影吗
something rated "pee pee 13"?
放屁垫果然很搞笑
Fart cushions are funny.
那个人在那  我开始紧张了
There's the guy. I'm getting a little nervous.
我在狂出汗了  就像《异乡劫历》里的人一样
I'm starting to sweat like those people on Locked up abroad.
也不知道为什么  我没走私海洛因啊
I don't know why. I haven't swallowed a heroin balloon.
好了  走吧
Okay, let's go.
假装我们上气不接下气
Pretend we're out of breath.
是喘不过气  不是脑子坏
Out of breath, not out of your mind.
抱歉
Hey, sorry.
我们能回到影厅一下吗
Can we just run back into the theater for a second?
我的手机落里面了
I left my iphone in there,
里面存着她的抗癫痫药处方呢
and the prescription for her anti-seizure medication's on it.
你们刚才哪个厅
Yeah, which theater were you in?
5号厅  看的是11点15的电影
Theatre five. Went to the 11:15.
1点20出来的
Got out at 1:20.
片子有点长  有十分钟的场景完全可以删掉
A little long. Could've cut ten from it.
你踏着自信又有所图谋的姿态
Wow, your walk with purpose is getting
跟阿憨的"敢在太岁头上动土"
almost as impressive as Han's "bang, bang,
一样让我令我刮目相看
You're in my house now, bitch!"
就是  阿憨怎么样
I know. What about Han?
事发前  我们还觉得他是个没枪53岁老头
Before yesterday, we thought he was 53 and unarmed.
看来我们每天都能多了解别人一点
Guess we learn something new about people every day.
对啊  我就了解到了当你一紧张
Yeah, like having to learn that when you get nervous,
就可以推我去死
I'm disposable.
那完全不是平时的我嘛
That was very uncharacteristic of me.
你好  哈利路亚
Hi, um, Hallelujah.
名字不错
Cool name, by the way.
今天过得好吗  哈利路亚
How are you doing today, Hallelujah?
有苦说不出
Bitter.
他们不让我在胸牌上加感叹号
They wouldn't let me put an exclamation point on my name tag.
你能不能给我们现做份爆米花
Um, is there any way you could make a fresh batch of popcorn?
能是能  但做新的要等10分钟
I could, but it takes ten minutes,
而你们的电影还有2分钟就开场了
and your show starts in two.
其实还有3分半
Actually, it takes 3 1/2,
而且预告片不看也无所谓
and I can miss a few trailers.
我以前也在电影院打工过
I used to work at a Cineplex Five.
所以你已经看透人间百态了是吗
Oh, so now you just know everything about life?
快点啦  一开场就会告诉观众
Come on, the opening scene sets up
男主角的超能力是怎么来的呢
where he gets his superpowers from.
喂  哈利路亚已经尽力了
Hey, Hallelujah here is doing the best he can.
我是说  从他名字看来
I mean, based on his name,
他的父母显然对他有更高的期望
his parents clearly had bigger dreams for him,
你们自己拖到开场前2分钟才来
and it is not his fault you guys showed up two minutes
又不是他的错
before the show starts.
或许下次你们可以早来个10分钟
Maybe next time, you'll show up ten minutes early
然后态度好点  唧唧歪歪少点
without the attitude and the fidgety exhaling.
你们以为哈利路亚听不见你们唧歪吗
You think Hallelujah doesn't hear that?
相当清楚哟
He does.
抱歉给你造成麻烦
Sorry to be such a problem.
我们随便来点现成的就好了
We'll just take whatever you've got ready.
不  姑娘  我挺你
No, girl. I got you.
我要给你做一桶现做的爆米花
I'm gonna make you a fresh batch.
哈利路亚  能给我也来点现做的吗
Hallelujah, could I have some fresh too?
烤焦的给你  吃不吃随便  死宅男
You'll get the burnt ones and like it, nerd.
咱们去那边坐吧
Let's sit down here.
地板上还没任何东西黏住我的鞋
Ooh, I'm not sticking to the floor yet.
看来这影院很高级呀
Fancy theater.
伙计们
Oh, hey, guys.
希望刚才没有对你们太过分
Hope I wasn't too hard on you out there.
斗篷不错
Nice cape.
谢谢  之前收在背包里了
Thanks. I had it in my backpack.
不确定该不该披
I wasn't sure.
你做得对
You made the right choice.
她喜欢我的斗篷
She likes my cape.
严格说来  她喜欢的是你姐姐的斗篷
Technically, she likes your sister's cape.
我对这些超级英雄的电影一无所知
Okay, so I don't know anything about these superhero movies.
这是翻拍的续集电影的前传吗
It's a remake of a prequel to a sequel?
-我脑子已经不转了  -好了  别说了
- I'm already confused. - Okay, stop.
主角总是那种书呆子宅男
So there's always a nerdy guy...
要么被人冤枉  或被某生物咬
and he's either been wronged or bitten
要么就是接触到什么毒
or exposed to something toxic.
然后就有了超能力
It gives him superpowers.
他爱上漂亮女人  而敌人则会试图杀她
He's in love with a pretty girl who his rival tries to kill
但女人不会死  因为还要拍第二部
but then won't because they have to make another movie.
而且通常有半裸镜头
Also, partial nudity,
植入式广告  超棒爆炸场面
product placement, dope explosions,
还伴随着汉斯·季默作曲的配乐
and a killer score by Hans Zimmer.
你对这些超级英雄电影的理解
Okay, your knowledge of these superhero movies
让我现在觉得性致盎然啊
is kind of turning me on right now.
慢着  开什么玩笑
Wait. Are you kidding me?
英雄小时候是红发啊
The hero has red hair as a child?
奇了怪了 他长大后
Um, weird, 'cause when he grows up,
头发可是黑色的
he has black hair.
是有化学品泄漏导致突变吗
Was there some sort of chemical spill,
而那跟漫画原作差了十万八千里
Which, by the way, wasn't in the original comic book!
-你当我是什么啊  傻子吗  -好了
- What am I, dumb? - Okay.
好了  别说了
Okay, come on.
走  我们去看其他电影吧
Come on, let's go to another movie.
你在说什么啊
What are you talking about?
你明摆着不喜欢这电影
Well, you obviously hate this.
你都冲着大屏幕嚷嚷了
You're yelling at the screen.
冲着大屏幕嚷嚷是看电影最爽的部分
Yelling at the screen is the best part of going to the movies,
你们白人应该多学着点
and more white people should learn that.
哇  快看啊
Oh, wow, look at that.
那辆车在那两个女生面前爆炸了
That car just exploded in front of those two girls,
而其中一个居然没有用另一个的身体
and one didn't use the other's body
来当人盾  抵挡飞射的破片残骸
to block her from the flying debris.
你什么时候才会说够啊
Are you ever gonna let this go?
我不知道  这件事对我影响很大
I don't know. I mean, it's kind of a big deal.
你置我于危险之中
You put my life in danger.
我都道过两次歉了
Well, I've apologized about it twice.
我不知道还有什么能做的了
I don't know how much more I can do.
是啊  我差点丧命
Yeah, I could have died,
但你都道过两次歉了  我们也算"扯平"了
but you apologized twice, so I guess we're good.
我不喜欢这部电影
I don't like this movie.
好多针对女性的暴力
It's violence against women.
我们去看凯瑟琳·海格尔的爱情喜剧系列吧
Let's go see that katherine Heigl rom-com sequel.
你有什么资格说"对女性的暴力行为"
Talk about violence against women.
我要去看凯瑟琳·海格尔了
I am gonna go spend some time with Katie Heigl.
至少她不会让我觉得内疚
At least she won't make me feel guilty.
回见
See ya.
享受三首情歌MV拼出来的烂片吧
Enjoy three Walking on sunshine montages.
我不想独自看电影
I don't wanna go to a movie by myself,
你说得对  我很抱歉
and you're right. I'm sorry.
我也讨厌自己那天的行为
I hate the way I acted.
我是个被宠坏的富家女  总是想着自己
I'm a spoiled rich girl, and I always put myself first,
我知道换做你  你一定不会这样做
and I know that's something you would never do.
闭嘴
Shut up.
麦克斯  我好像看见阿憨了
Max, I think I just saw Han.
就是他  他在这里干嘛
It is Han. What's he doing here?
为什么他要坐这么靠后
Why is he sitting all the way in the back?
不知道  以为自己能挡住任何人的视线吧
I don't know, maybe he's afraid of blocking absolutely no one's view.
跟他在一起的男人和女人是谁啊
And who is that guy and girl he's sitting with?
阿憨不会是在玩3P吧
Is Han in a threesome?
-难道他是游戏女人堆的浪子  -拜托
- Does he secretly have game? - Please.
阿憨唯一能玩的"游戏"就是唱儿歌
The only game Han has is "one, two, buckle my shoe."
慢着  他走了
Wait, he's leaving,
他旁边坐的那家伙也走了
and so is the guy he was sitting next to.
阿憨是不是变得比电影更有趣了
Did Han just get more interesting?
我们得跟着他
We have to follow him.
他可以用意念把一堵墙炸掉
He can blast a wall apart with his thoughts,
却挣脱不了一副手铐吗
but he can't get out of Handcuffs?
连我这种普通人都能把手铐搞定
Even I could get out of Handcuffs!
祝你们被电影骗得愉快
Have fun being lied to.
你说得对  你永远是对的
You're right. You're always right.
你有对象了吗
Are you seeing anyone?
我都看不下去了
That was hard to watch.
为什么他要跟那个陌生人去厕所呢
Why is he going to the bathroom with that stranger?
难道阿憨是共和党参议员吗
Is Han also a republican senator?
带位员
Usher.